A beautiful day begins.
We also went for a walk to the market and supermarket.
This afternoon I'm going to make some side dishes.
Mako was basking in the sun, looking very comfortable.
The best thing for me is to stay healthy.
The basil I've been growing since summer is growing big.
The shiso flowered and went to seed.
Now, the first step is to make boiled eggs.
It's easy to microwave! You can do it with a simple microwave!
When I buy vegetables, I wash them all together.
When you make reserve dishes, they're not fresh! It's bad for you! Some people always get angry.
Japanese people have long been raised in a culture of preservation.
We use salt and sugar to make our food last longer, and we eat a little bit of all kinds of food every day.
Kaiseki cuisine is the culmination of all this.
By eating a variety of foods little by little, the result will be a better balance of nutrition and
Your own body can excrete things that are said to be bad for you.
Also, the way food is prepared, cooked, and seasoned Japanese food is different from all other countries.
For example, sashimi and sushi are good examples.
There is a culture of eating them raw.
Instead, the way it is prepared, fastened, and cut is completely different from other food cultures.
The concept of umami also originated in Japan.
Now, famous chefs overseas are learning about it and adopting it in their cooking.
Many of you have raised the concern about sodium nitrite in your side dishes.
In Japan, there is no written information about it, and it is not even discussed.
The only information available is as a food additive, if any.
Nitrite is a major food additive.
It is used everywhere, from coloring to preventing food from spoiling.
Processed meat such as commercial ham, sausage, and bacon, cod roe, cooked sake, and
And of course, it is always in stunt foods.
So, don't be afraid of nitrites because they are bad for you! It's not a matter of
Don't take too much every day, just take as much as your body can excrete.
Japanese couples think so.
We prep food in batches like this once a week and consume it over four or five days.
Of course, it is better to cook fresh food every day, but many Japanese dishes taste better the next day.
If we cook together, it makes cooking for ourselves easier and we can eat a little bit of everything at a time.
I am not recommending that the cooking methods used by Japanese mothers are absolutely fine! This is not to say that I am recommending that the way Japanese mothers cook is absolutely fine!
Interesting to see the Japanese food culture on YouTube! Cross-cultural exchange is interesting!
Think of it that way and take it easy on yourself.
Also, Taiwanese people are not very fond of microwaves.
But do you all have a smartphone? You use a refrigerator and air conditioning, right?
There's a debate to be had about whether it's good or not.
As a housewife who cooks meals every day, I think it's okay to use what's convenient, don't you? That's what I think.
We've been using it at my parents' house since I was in kindergarten.
I know many of its benefits.
The way to make your microwave oven work is to use it correctly and make sure it does not malfunction. In short, maintenance is everything.
Microwaves are really useful when single ingredients are used as a point of reference.
I would not use it to heat up my lunch as it is.
Whoa, whoa, whoa! It's time to get serious and start building!
I don't have any menu in mind beforehand.
I improvise after I get home using ingredients that are fresh or cheap that day.
This is also a daily habit.
These were emperor beans, weren't they? Thank you for telling me!
Next, I bought some frozen shrimp from Costco.
Go straight to Lekue, I N!
A pinch of salt
rice wine
Mix lightly.
Steam in a microwave oven.
Mix the steamed shrimp with the emperor beans.
salt
garlic powder
I use these things because they are useful.
Chidori vinegar from Kyoto
Cold-pressed extra virgin olive oil
black pepper
Mix lightly.
Garlic Marinated Shrimp and Emperor Beans" is ready!
This is a side dish that tastes great even after it has cooled down for a couple of days.
Cut off the stem of the eggplant.
Make a fine decorative knife.
Cut into long, thin quarters.
Lekue again.
It's so convenient that I use it all the time.
Just microwave it!
Cut green beans into bite-sized pieces.
Make sure the eggplant is well cooked.
To enamel container
Make sure to grate the fresh ginger as this is an important part of the flavor.
MUJI Ponzu, which I bought the other day.
Add the same amount of water because it is a little thick at this point.
Sesame oil for flavored pickles
Mix lightly.
I'm sure you'll like it.
It also tastes best after a few days rather than on the same day!
I took the eggs under cold water and let them cool.
Then the shell will come off smoothly.
Place in a storage bag
A seasoning from my husband's hometown, Kan koji (the koji used to make shio koji is made from glutinous rice)
Add water, mix, and your koji egg is ready to use.
Boiled eggs must be eaten within two days, but koji eggs can be stored for a week.
Bring a pot of water to a boil.
Bean sprouts are cheap, tasty, and nutritious.
I'll keep finishing up the other vegetables.
I n salted water, add the snap peas!
I'll boil the four seasons beans together with the time difference.
Add lemon to the boiling water.
salt
pepper
grated garlic
Do not overdo it! It's just for flavoring.
Extra virgin avocado oil*See summary section for details
Coat well with oil.
[Beet and Four Seasons Beans Marinated in Lemon] Finished!
It's delicious just the way it is.
Start boiling the bok choy from the hard part.
When the roots are cooked, submerge the leaves in hot water.
When it's cooked, rinse it with water.
Next, spinach.
Immediately after boiling, soak in cold water.
This is a cooking method that all Japanese people know.
Next, bean sprouts.
Nilaa also I N by time!
Chives can be eaten raw, so you'll want to lightly cook them.
The nutritional value also escapes me.
grated garlic
salt
Honjozo soy sauce, Japanese soy sauce does not contain sugar and is not sweet
sesame oil
It can't not be good!
I'm not sure if I'll be able to make it.
Store in the refrigerator and eat up in 3 or 4 days.
Cut the bok choy into bite-sized pieces.
Squeeze out the water and put into an enamel container.
Moisture will damage the food faster.
Here is a low-sodium salted kelp.
Sprinkle with a few sprinkles
Concentrated Soba Soup
Mix lightly
Sprinkle with roasted sesame seeds.
[Bok choy with salted kelp] is ready - can be stored in the refrigerator for 4 to 5 days.
Cut spinach into bite-sized pieces.
Squeeze out the water well.
firm tofu
Cut off about 100 grams.
Lekue for 30 seconds!
Rinsing makes it easier to drain the water.
Wrap in kitchen paper and squeeze out the water.
Mix the spinach with the spinach, breaking it up with your hands.
salt
(soup) stock
a little mirin
Mix well.
ground toasted sesame seeds
Mix it up.
I'd prefer to mash the tofu more cleanly before adding it, because I'm a lazy person.
If it tastes good, it's OK!
It's a great way to add a little something extra to your meal.
Dried hijiki from Kyushu
In fact, I stocked up on Japanese ingredients again because of Rakuten's shipping campaign last month.
Soak in water and set aside.
Shave the carrots finely.
Shaving scratches the surface of the vegetable, making it easier for the flavor to soak in than cutting with a knife.
Thinly slice the burdock.
Soak in vinegar water to remove scum.
Cut the eringi into pieces.
Place in a heatproof container.
Leftover potatoes from last week
Cut into bite-sized pieces.
Place in a heatproof container.
salt
Spray type avocado oil, Italian herb flavor
Spray evenly.
Add garlic powder for a punch.
black pepper
Oh, we had some cherry tomatoes left over, so let's add them in together.
Place in a toaster oven and bake slowly at 180 degrees for 30 minutes.
Cut a large green pepper in half.
Cut into bite-sized pieces.
Remove the stems, but leave the seeds intact.
Cut the chives into bite-sized pieces.
Avocado oil in a frying pan.
Roast the peppers with the seeds intact.
This is a recipe from Tamori in Japan.
It's really easy and delicious, so I hope you'll try it.
Bake until slightly browned.
Yamaki's Mentsuyu in!
After boiling it down a little.
It's so delicious!
Next is the end of the garlic head.
Fresh chili peppers given to me by a man at the market.
Then drained burdock slices.
Grill over high heat until crispy.
Season with salt.
when fried
Pepperoncino with burdock is ready.
A snack for drinks~.
Put sesame oil in an enameled cast iron pan.
Water-rehydrated hijiki
Fry lightly.
Break up the shimeji mushrooms by hand and add them.
finely chopped carrot
Fry lightly.
rice wine
mirin containing alcohol
soy sauce
(plain) white soup
water
If you have a return, just use the return and water.
shredded deep-fried tofu
Mix lightly.
Cook over medium heat for about 10 minutes.
In the meantime - sesame oil in a frying pan
finely chopped carrot
Maitake mushrooms, broken into small pieces
Stir-fry.
This is the kimchi I bought at Jeonryon.
Put all the rest in.
Stir-fry.
This kimchi had an elegant taste with just the right amount of acidity. Highly recommended.
After frying well, put in the chives.
Stir-fry until cooked through.
I'm not sure if I'll be able to make it.
It can be served as a side dish with rice or as a garnish for ramen.
I'm sure you'll like it.
In Taiwan, hijiki is a luxury item. I was a bit stingy, so it doesn't have much presence.
You can also add it to white rice to make mixed rice.
It can be stored in the refrigerator for one week.
This one's done.
Grilled eringi, potatoes and tomatoes with herbs
I don't know why tomatoes become so sweet when they are cooked a little.
Can be stored in the refrigerator for 4 to 5 days.
2 cups washed rice
Shave off one piece of raw corn.
To Vermicula I H Iron Pot
Don't throw away the core, just put it in the pot.
30 ml (2 tablespoons) white soup stock
Add water to 2 cups scale.
Add a little salt to make the corn sweeter.
Then pour in the broth water.
Add a little bit of water.
I'll cook it.
Oh yeah, a big bunch of Chinese cabbage was 10 yuan!
Make [Genovese sauce with fragrant greens] to keep well.
First, chop the well-drained Chinese cabbage into small pieces.
To the ball.
Mixed nuts at home
Take out the cashews and walnuts from there.
Chop with a knife.
2 cloves garlic
Lightly chop.
In!
salt
A generous amount of extra virgin olive oil.
Stir with a handheld mixer.
I don't add cheese because it doesn't keep well.
It will keep for about a week if refrigerated.
Dare the pasta and top it with cheese for a superb taste.
When the mixture is emulsified and smooth, it's ready.
Packed in disinfected jars.
Shake to release the air.
Cover the top surface with olive oil to prevent it from being exposed to air.
Scoop up the bottom when you use it.
Last but not least - dried shiitake mushrooms that have been rehydrated in water
Slice thinly
Squeeze the remaining tofu well.
I'll destroy it.
Ground pork from the market (twice ground, fine type)
I N the tofu!
Add 3.5 grams of salt per 200 grams of tofu and 1 percent of 150 grams of ground meat.
Dried Hijiki
Keep going, I N!
carrot
dried shiitake mushroom
2 tablespoons potato starch
Knead well.
Roll up and put into a storage container.
It makes it easier for me to prepare dinner.
Elbows will also soften if left for a day or more, and they will absorb excess water.
[Tofu and hijiki hamburger steak seeds] are ready - I'll bake and eat them within a couple of days!
Rice with corn" is ready to cook.
I cooked a lot of rice, so I think I'll eat it as is tonight and make onigiri tomorrow.
The soup stock is delicious as it is.
This week's side dish is ready.
Marinated Shrimp and Emperor Beans with Garlic] [Easy Soaked Eggplant with Ponzu Sauce] [Pepperoncino with Burdock] [Genovese Sauce with Fragrant Greens
[Chives and Bean Sprouts Namuru] [Chives Maitake [Beet Bowl Beans and Four Seasons Beans Marinated in Lemon] Stir-fried Kimchi] [Stewed Hijiki
[Grilled and soaked green pepper] [Salted kelp of bok choy] [Tofu paste with spinach] [Cloth dressing] [Herb grilled eringi, potato and tomato] [Tofu and hijiki hamburger steak seeds
koji egg
Rice with corn
Good work.
Oh, delicious!
Bon appétit!